<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://fahmon.net/news/styles/feed.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/">
<channel>
<title>FahMon News</title>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news</link>
<description>News and development of FahMon</description>
<dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2010-11-12T13:09:39-06:00</dc:date>
<admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://nanoblogger.sourceforge.net" />
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2010/11/12/index.php#e2010-11-12T12_55_55.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.99.4 Released</title>
<dc:date>2010-11-12T12:55:55-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.99.4 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get it.</p> 
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the homepage.</p> 
<p>What's new in this release</p> 
<ul>
<li>New core support and fixed parsing of others.
<li>Pause detection works properly now.
<li>Update available window will show version numbers on subsequent updates.
<li>Benchmarks database now stored in xml format. 
</ul> 
<p>As always if you find any bugs in the FahMon please report them using <a href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">trac</a></p> ]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2010/10/19/index.php#e2010-10-19T17_39_30.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.99.3 Released</title>
<dc:date>2010-10-19T17:39:30-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.99.3 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get 
it.</p> 
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the homepage.</p> 
<p>What's new in this release</p> 
<ul> 
<li>New core support.
<li>Fixed Windows Vista/7 DEP/C++ runtime crash
<li>Fixed projects.dat not deleting on Windows
</ul> 
<p>As always if you find any bugs in the FahMon please report them using <a 
href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">trac</a></p> ]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2010/10/17/index.php#e2010-10-17T16_09_52.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.99.2 Released</title>
<dc:date>2010-10-17T16:09:52-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.99.2 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get it.</p> 
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the homepage.</p> 
<p>What's new in this release</p> 
<ul> 
<li>New core support.
<li>Fixed thread-safety issues.
<li>Projects database now stored in xml format.
</ul> 
<p>As always if you find any bugs in the FahMon please report them using <a href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">trac</a></p> ]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2009/04/06/index.php#e2009-04-06T08_59_32.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.99.1 Released</title>
<dc:date>2009-04-06T08:59:32-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.99.1 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get 
it.</p>
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the homepage.</p>
<p>What's new in this release</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a nasty crash-bug which affected Windows users monitoring linux clients. This also cleans up 
some behaviour that affects all platforms
</ul>
<p>As always if you find any bugs in the FahMon please report them using <a 
href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">trac</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2009/04/03/index.php#e2009-04-03T17_34_38.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.99 Released</title>
<dc:date>2009-04-03T17:34:38-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.99 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get 
it.</p>
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the homepage.</p>
<p>A bit of what's new in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Removed WU info panel from default view.
<li>Lots of performance changes.
<li>You can now monitor clients via FTP and HTTP.
<li>You can upload web output to an FTP server automatically.
</ul>
<p><b>What happened to 2.4.0?</b><br />
As a result of the performance and memory fixes, a previously infrequent crash-bug has increased in 
prevalence and will take more time to fix. Since this is still unlikely to occur often I'm releasing the 
current code as it stands. 2.4.0 will be released as soon as this crash-bug is fixed.</p>

<p>As always if you find any bugs in FahMon please report them using <a 
href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">trac</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2009/01/17/index.php#e2009-01-17T09_35_13.txt</link>
<title>FahMon IRC Channel now online</title>
<dc:date>2009-01-17T09:35:13-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Website</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>For those of you wanting online support or to discuss the development of FahMon, there is now an 
official IRC channel on freenode.net at #fahmon.<br />
<a href="irc://freenode.net/%23fahmon">Join #fahmon on freenode in your IRC client</a><br />
<a href="http://widget.mibbit.com/?server=irc.freenode.net&channel=%23fahmon">Join #fahmon on freenode 
with the mibbit web IRC client</a>
</p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2008/11/04/index.php#e2008-11-04T18_05_18.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.4 Released</title>
<dc:date>2008-11-04T18:05:18-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.4 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get 
it.</p>
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changlog which is linked to from the homepage.</p>
<p>What's new in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>This version fixes the nasty bug in 2.3.3 which cause clients to fail to update after non-specific 
periods of time. This was caused by a typo in the update queue handler which now works properly.
<li>CPU usage has been reduced slightly when refreshing clients thanks to a re-worked message logger.
<li>clientstab.txt is now tab-delimited. This has no effect on FahMon, but may break compatibility with 
other tools that read this file.
</ul>
<p>As always if you find any bugs in FahMon please report them using <a 
href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">trac</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2008/11/01/index.php#e2008-11-01T13_11_52.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.3 Released</title>
<dc:date>2008-11-01T13:11:52-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.3 is now available for download. Please see the download page for details on how to get 
it.</p>
<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the home 
page.</p>
<p>What's new in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>The client list view has been made much more configurable and additional columns can be added with a 
right click on the column title.
<li>You can now completely hide the WU Info panel on the right hand side of the main FahMon window.
<li>Clients can now be managed from the main menu instead of a right click menu in the clients list.
<li>Clients can now be manually disabled if you don't want FahMon to monitor them.
<li>Paused clients can now be detected and shouldn't register as *hung*.
<li>A number of debilitating bugs that affected GPU monitoring have been fixed.
<li>FahMon on Windows now follows MS guidelines for storage of settings. This means no more problems with 
UAC on Vista when downloading project updates.
</ul>
<p>Special thanks go to John Daiker for providing a number of patches to improve GPU2 support as well as 
fixing the "quick-refresh" crash bug.</p>
<p>As always if you find any bugs in FahMon please report them using <a 
href="http://trac.fahmon.net">trac</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2008/06/16/index.php#e2008-06-16T11_48_49.txt</link>
<title>Upcoming developments and contributions</title>
<dc:date>2008-06-16T11:48:49-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Development</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>I'm writing this news post mainly to let members of the community know what's going on with FahMon development-wise, since there have been no new announcements since 
April.</p>
<b>Developments</b>
<p>For those of you who are not aware, FahMon is coded entirely in my spare time, which recently I have had virtually none of (writing theses was the main culprit). 
However, I'm about to start a major drive to get various bits of core code in FahMon up to scratch and more stable.<br />There are already a number of GUI enhancements in 
svn including re-organised menus (for those who were confused about the lack of a "client" menu), configurable columns in the main view and the ability to hide the "WU 
Information" panel. There may be a few more tweaks to the GUI being made of the next few days to try and make the whole thing a little slicker than in the current 
release.<br />After finishing the GUI updates I'll be taking a look at the innards of the monitoring code, and possibly re-writing major portions of it to increase 
stability, and compatibility (mainly with SMP clients inside Virtual Machines).</p>
<p>I also hope to be able to put together some build-bots to automatically compile the latest svn code to ease the testing process.</p>
<b>Contributing</b>
<p>There are a number of ways that you can help contribute to the development of FahMon, and only 1 of them requires you to have any programming knowledge:</p>
<ul>
<li>Bug reporting. This is <i>very</i> important to help improve FahMon, because unless I know a bug exists, I can't fix it.
<li>Ideas for features. You guys might come up with something I had'nt thought of.
<li>Code contributions. I welcome any patches to code, from typos to new functions.
<li>Monetary donations. There's a paypal link on the homepage. There's no obligation, but if you want to donate, the facility is there.
</ul>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<link>http://fahmon.net/news/archives/2008/04/11/index.php#e2008-04-11T17_50_09.txt</link>
<title>FahMon 2.3.2b Released.</title>
<dc:date>2008-04-11T17:50:09-06:00</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Andrew Schofield</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Releases</dc:subject>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p>FahMon 2.3.2b is now available for download. See the download page for details on how to get it.</p>

<p>For a comprehensive list of changes please view the changelog which is linked to from the home page and the download page.</p>

<p>What's new in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Several behavioural fixes to dialogs and a number of visual fixes including displaying fractional deadlines correctly.
<li>Windows now maximises from the System tray correctly. Finally.
<li>A number of performance and behaviour tweaks to the OS X build.
<li>GPU2 core support.
</ul>
<p>Special thanks go to Mark Gerby (Gerby19) for helping me debug and test some of the Windows bugs</p>
<p>To activate GPU2 support you may need to update the project list from the "FahMon" menu.</p>
<p>As always if you find any bugs in FahMon please report them using <a href="http://trac.fahmon.net/">
trac.</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
